The subject's name is John Kramer,
解剖对象是约翰·克里莫
a 52-year-old male Caucasian.
52岁，白种男性
He's seen better days.
曾经风光一时
We have a recent rectangular transection to the left occipital lobe.
左脑枕叶部位有个近期的方形切口
Some kind of backdoor brain surgery.
看起来是次地下颅部手术
Let's check the stomach.
看看胃里有什么
What the hell?
什么鬼东西？
Get homicide here, now.
把凶杀科的人找来，快点！
Where is it?
哪里找到的
It was in his stomach.
胃里面
Cut it out.
切开它
Are you there, detective?
是你吗，警探？
If so, you are probably
如果是的话，你可能就是
the last man standing.
最后一个活着的人了
Now perhaps you will succeed where the others have failed.
现在可能你做到了其他人做不到的
You think you will walk away untested?
你以为你能不接受考验就离开？
I promise
我保证
that my work will continue.
我的事业仍将继续
You think it's over just because I' dead?
你以为我死了就结束了？
It's not over.
还没结束
The games have just begun.
游戏才刚刚开始
What the fuck? What the fuck?
什么鬼东西？什么鬼东西？
What the fuck?
什么鬼东西？
My eyes!
我的眼睛
What the fuck? What the fuck?
什么鬼东西？什么鬼东西？
What the fuck is this?
什么鬼东西？
Who's that?
谁在那儿？
Talk to me. What are you doing?
说话？你在干嘛？
Talk to me.
说话
Stop it!
停下
Stop.
Stop it.
停下
What are you doing to me?
你在对我做什么？
What did I do? Help!
我犯了什么错？ 救命！
Help!
救命！
Who's doing this to me?
谁在那里？
Just get away from me!
别靠近我！
What did I do?
我犯了什么错？
《电锯惊魂4》
- Right side clear. - Left side clear.
- 右边安全 - 左边安全
Clear.
安全
In position. Standing by.
各就各位 原地待命
Hold right there.
别动！
I see movement.
有动静
We have a device.
机器人来了
You get eyes in there before you go in.
让机器人先进去
Get some eyes in here.
放摄像头进去
Moving now.
正在设置
The doorway is clear.
门口安全
It's Kerry!
是凯瑞！
- Rigg! - Don't do it! We're not secure!
- 瑞格！ - 别动，不安全！
- Rigg, I said no! - Kerry!
- 瑞格，我说了别动！ - 凯瑞！
- Stop him! - Do not go through that door.
- 停下他 - 别进那扇门
Kerry!
凯瑞！
Shit.
靠！
- Get me the coroner's office. - Copy.
- 把验尸官找来 - 收到
Somebody get those rats off her.
谁把她身上的老鼠弄掉
Let's get the light on this.
去把灯打开
Cut her down.
把她弄下来
You know I can't do that.
你知道我不能
I said cut her down.
我说把她弄下来
Please.
拜托
Are you trying to get yourself killed?
你想找死吗？
You know never to go through an unsecured door, ever.
你知道永远不要乱闯没确认安全的门 永远
I thought she was still alive,
我只是以为她还活着
thought I could save her.
以为我能救她
Did you ever think that we would end up here when we first started?
你有没有想过一开始，我们就会死在这里？
No.
没
I didn't see it happening like this.
我从没见过这样的事
Why the hell do we still do it?
那为什么我们还要做？
It's in our nature to save them.
救他们这是我们的本能
- It's what we do. - Right.
- 这是我们的工作 - 对
"Cherish Your Life."
“珍惜你的生命”
- What? - The fucking motto.
- 什么 - TMD标语
We're supposed to cherish our lives.
我们应该珍惜我们的生命
How the hell are we supposed to do that
如果这就是我们的生活
when this is our life?
我们要怎么珍惜？
We chose this.
我们选择了这个
- You go home. - Hoffman, there are two agents
- 你回去 - 霍夫曼，两个特别警探
- here to see you. - Copy.
- 要见你 - 知道了
- Detective Hoffman? - Yes.
- 霍夫曼警探？ - 是的
I' special agent Lindsey Perez.
我是特别警探琳达丝·派瑞兹
This is special agent Peter Strahm.
这是特别警探彼特·史特姆
How can I help the FBI?
我能为FBI做点什么？
We're here about detective Kerry. She was our liaison.
我们来这里是因为凯瑞警探 她是我们的联络员
"Open the door and you will find me."
“打开门就能找到我”
What?
什么？
- What's this? - The key that came
- 这是什么？ - 这把钥匙
with out last message from detective Kerry.
和凯瑞警探给我们的最后消息在一起
"Open the door and you will find me" mean anything to you?
“打开门就能找到我”对你来说意味着什么？
No.
不
Where's the body?
尸体在哪里？
The crime scene photographer's flash picked up this bullet casing.
犯罪现场摄影师的灯光照到这个弹壳
It was lodged between the body and the device.
在尸体和设备之间
Run it for prints.
检查下指纹
Give us the room for a minute, would you? Thanks.
方便回避一下么？谢谢
The lock was open.
锁打开了
She couldn't get out.
她不可能逃掉
It was constructed for her execution. Betrayed the rules.
这就是为她的死刑造的，违反了规则
Not a Jigsaw trap then?
所以这不是竖锯的陷阱
No, Amanda Young, the accomplice...
不是，阿曼达·杨，那个同伙…
- This wasn't done by Amanda Young. - Excuse me?
- 这不可能是阿曼达·杨干的 - 对不起？
Detective Kerry weighed approximately 130 lbs.
凯瑞警探大约130磅
Amanda Young's arrest report has her at 107.
阿曼达·杨被捕时107磅
- She couldn't get her up there alone. - John Kramer was...
- 她不可能一个人把她弄上去 - 约翰·克里莫是…
The bedridden cancer patient? He's brains, not brawn.
那个卧病在床的癌症患者？ 他只能能动脑子，干不了体力活的
He was also an engineer. He could have rigged pulleys...
他还是个工程师 他可以用机械的办法
Or someone else could have helped him.
或者找个人帮他
Special agent, if you're here for any other reason than just to assist...
特别探员，如果你来这里不是为了帮忙…
We're here to find the person your department couldn't, detective,
我们来这里只是找一个你们找不到的人，警探
the one helping Jigsaw and Amanda Young.
那个帮助竖锯还有阿曼达·杨的人
Excuse me.
对不起
We found a harlequin doll in your possession. What's that about?
我们在你这里发现了这个小丑玩具 这是怎么回事？
It's a toy. The kids play with toys.
只是个玩具 小孩都爱玩具
That's all it is.
仅此而已
How about the tricycle?
那这个三轮车呢？
The tricycle is from John's youth.
这个三轮车是约翰年轻时候的
A grown man has a tricycle his whole life?
成年人把一辆三轮车保存了一生？
I' sure you've kept things that were important to you.
我肯定你也会把你重要的东西保存下来的
Look, Ms. Tuck,
听着，塔克女士
is there any reason we should be concerned for your safety?
有什么理由我们需要保护你的安全？
Perhaps you should be more concerned for yourself.
也许你更需要保护自己的安全
Why don't you tell me everything you know about John?
为什么不告诉我们你所知道约翰的一切
And let's start at the beginning.
让我们从头开始
John's life defies chronology and linear description.
约翰一生都在反对年代学还有顺序描述
So why don't we start at the end and work our way backwards?
那么我们为什么不从最后开始往回看？
I represent Ms. Tuck.
我代表塔克女士
She knows something.
她知道一些事情
I thought you were going home.
我以为你回家了
You have vacation time, right? Take it.
你有假期的，对吗？ 用掉它
Finish the remodeling, spend some time with Tracy.
完成你家的重新装修 陪陪翠西
- She understands. - Then don't take her for granted.
- 她能理解 - 别想当然
- Eric is still out there, man. - Eric's been missing for six months.
- 艾瑞克还在受折磨，兄弟 - 艾瑞克已经失踪六个月了
Kerry was gone for four days. I can only be as optimistic
凯瑞也死了四天了，只能有点阿Q精神
- as the facts allow. - Yeah, well, I' in it till I find him.
- 但都已经发生了啊 - 是的，嗯，我在找到他之前不会走的
Finding his body is not gonna vindicate us.
找到他的尸体说明不了什么
Finding him alive will.
如果他活着就能
It's time to let go.
是时候放手了
I want you to go home.
我要你回家
I'll call you later to make sure everything is okay.
我晚点打电话给你确认一切正常
Who's he?
他是谁？
Lieutenant Rigg, our SWAT commander.
瑞格中尉，我们特警队的队长
- What's his problem? - Everyone around him keeps dying.
- 他怎么了？ - 他身边的人一个个死掉
What's it say?
里面写些什么？
It says, " I tried calling you four times."
写了“打了四次电话给你”
It says, "dinner is in the fridge."
写了“晚饭在冰箱里”
And at the bottom it says, "I love you."
最下面是"我爱你"
I need to help my mom for a few days.
我要去帮我妈妈几天
Just...
只是
come with me, okay? Now.
跟我一起去，好吗？ 现在
I can't.
我不能
You can,
你可以
but you won't.
但你不愿意
What you can't do is save everyone.
你不可能拯救每个人
Tracy.
翠西
Tracy, please listen to me.
翠西，你听我说
John Kramer owned a company called The Urban Renewal Group.
约翰·克里莫有个公司名字叫“城市再生集团”
No irony in that, huh?
够讽刺，不是吗？
What was Rigg watching?
瑞格在看什么
Jill Tuck's interrogation. She was Jigsaw's ex. It's old.
吉尔·塔克的审问 她是竖锯的前妻，老故事了
Why is a SWAT guy watching that?
为什么一个特警队员会看这个？
Strahm, I really think we should tell Hoffman
史特姆，我真的觉得我们应该告诉霍夫曼
what detective Kerry said in her last message.
凯瑞警探最后告诉我们的消息
She said two officers might be in danger,
说两个警官可能有危险
but until we know who, we're not causing a panic.
但是在我们知道是谁之前我不想制造恐慌
If detective Hoffman or anyone else in this precinct is in danger,
如果霍夫曼警探或者这个辖区内的任何一个人有危险
- I think they should know it. - Not your call.
- 我觉得他们应该知道 - 不是你说了算
Making any progress?
有什么进展？
We're fine, thanks.
我们很好，谢谢
Hey, boss, looks like another doctor went missing from the hospital.
嘿，老板，看起来又有一个医生从医院消失了
- Maybe it's... - Thanks.
- 可能是… - 谢谢
I'll check it out.
我会弄清楚的
If you need me, call my cell. Coffee machine is around the corner.
如果需要的话打我手机 咖啡机在角落那边
- A boy or a girl? - A girl.
- 男孩还是女孩？ - 女孩
- I didn't know you were married. - I' not.
- 我都不知道你已经结婚了 - 没有
It's a short story, believe me.
相信我，这只是个很短的故事
Tracy.
翠西
Tracy?
翠西？
Hello, Officer Rigg.
你好，瑞格警官
Welcome to your rebirth.
欢迎来到你的重生考验
Fuck.
操
For years you've stood by and witnessed as your colleagues have fallen.
这几年来你一直见证着你同事的死
You have remained untouched
艾瑞克·马修斯失踪了
while Eric Matthews has disappeared.
你却没事
But with your survival came your obsession...
但是你的幸存给你带来了困扰
obsession to stop those around you
你不知道怎么停止周围的人
from making the wrong choices,
做错误的选择
thus preventing you from making the right ones.
而这影响到了你的正确选择
You wanted to save everyone.
你想拯救每个人
Tonight I give you the opportunity
今晚我给你一个机会
to face your obsession. Look closely.
面对你的困扰 看清楚了
Eric Matthews is still alive.
艾瑞克·马修斯还活着
- Eric. - The block of ice he stands upon is melting.
- 艾瑞克 - 他脚下的冰正在融化
He has but 90 minutes to save himself.
他只有90分钟拯救自己
Detective Hoffman's fate is linked to Eric's survival.
霍夫曼警探和他命悬一线
Heed my warning, Officer Rigg.
记住的我警告 瑞格警官
Their lives hang in the balance
他们的生死取决于你
of your obsession.
是否能解决你的困扰
Will you learn how to let go and truly save them?
你能学会会放手，真正的解救他们吗？
The choice is yours.
自己选择
Don't fucking move.
别动！
Jesus.
天哪
Take off the mask. Put your hands in the air.
拿开面具 把手举起来
I can't!
我不能！
Officer Rigg, your first test.
瑞格警官 你的第一个测验
The person in front of you is in desperate need of help.
你前面这个人 现在很绝望，需要你帮助
But it is not your job to save them.
但是救他们不是你的职责
You view this person as a victim.
你认为这个人是个受害者
But if you want to see what I see,
但如果你看到了我看到的
beneath the mask lies a criminal undeserving of the life she leads.
面具下面是一个本不该活到今天的罪犯
Your obsession tells you to save the victim.
你的困扰让你想救这个受害者
I tell you to walk away. The choice is yours.
我让你走开 自己选择
- Are you a cop? - What?
- 你是警察？ - 什么？
- Are you a cop? - Yeah, I' a cop.
- 你是警察？ - 是，我是警察
What is that? What did you do?
这是什么？你做了什么？
- They're in the gears. - What's in the gears?
- 它们在齿轮里面 - 什么在齿轮里面？
The combination. Get me out.
密码 让我出去
Cut my hair. Just get me out. Cut my hair.
剪掉我的头发，让我出去 剪掉我的头发
- Relax, relax. - Hurry!
- 放松，放松 - 快点
Fucking cut my hair, please.
TMD剪掉我的头发，求你了
Get me out!
让我出去!
Please. Where are you going?
求你了，你要去干吗？
Wait wait wait wait.
等等，等等，等等
Wait wait.
等等
- Shit. - Wait!
- 靠 - 等等
Stop!
停下！
Fucking let me out!
TMD让我出去
Get back here, you fucking!
回来，你这个贱人
Okay, I' sorry. Please come back.
好的，对不起，请回来
Where the hell is the combination?
密码TM在什么地方？
Shit. Shit.
靠，靠
Hold on! Hold on!
坚持住！坚持住！
I got one.
找到一个
I got one. Hold on!
找到一个，坚持住！
- Hold on. - Hurry!
- 坚持住 - 快点！
Oh, God.
噢，天哪
- Yeah? - We pulled a print off that casing.
- 什么？ - 弹壳上找到个指纹
We've got a match.
发现了是谁的
Jesus. Did you check this?
天哪，你确认？
Twice.
两遍了
Come on, come on, come on.
快点，快点
I got another one. Hold on!
又找到一个，坚持住
- Hold on. Hold on. - Hurry!
- 坚持住，坚持住！ - 快点
I got it. 617. 617.
知道了，617，617
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
坚持，坚持，坚持！
Go!
走！
Shit.
靠！
Okay okay okay, listen,
好，好，好，听着
stay here. Don't touch anything.
呆在这，别乱碰东西
What the fuck?
什么狗屁？
What the fuck are you doing? What are you doing?
你TM在干嘛？ 你在干嘛？
Drop the fucking knife!
TMD放下刀子
- Please. - Put the knife down.
- 拜托 - 放下刀
Put the knife down.
放下刀
I just saved your fucking life.
我刚刚才救了你的狗命
- I' gonna kill you! - Drop the knife.
- 我要杀了你 - 放下刀
Hey, these prints just came in. They're from Officer Rigg.
嘿，指纹找到了 是瑞格警官的
- Fisk. - Not now.
- 费史克 - 现在不行
We just got a call of "shots fired" from 23 Park Place.
我们接到报警说23区有枪声
That's Rigg's apartment.
那是瑞格的房子
Hello, Brenda.
你好，布兰达
I want to play a game.
我要跟你玩个游戏
An officer will try to save you.
一个警官将会试着救你
If he is successful, then your game begins.
如果他成功了，你的游戏就开始了
This man will use these photos
这个人会用这些照片
to sentence you for your crimes.
指控你的罪行
And the only way to stop him
唯一的阻止办法
is taped underneath the TV.
就在电视机下的柜子里面
Let him save your life and accept your fate to rot in prison,
让他救你，然后把你送进监狱
or kill him and guarantee your freedom.
或者杀了他，重获自由
Make your choice.
自己选择
（有人救人…有人杀人）
I'll fucking kill you,
我TM杀了你
you fucking bitch!
你个狗娘养的
Rigg!
瑞格
- Rigg, you in here? Rigg! - Go! Move move move!
- 瑞格，你在里面么？瑞格 - 走，走走走！
Christ.
天哪
I got one.
找到一个
It's started.
开始了
An APB has been issued for Rigg. Everybody's looking.
瑞格被全境通缉了 所有人都在找他
- He has a wife. Where is she? - We haven't located her yet.
- 他有个老婆，在哪里？ - 还没找到
Strahm...
史特姆
two detectives. You see this?
两个警探，你看到了这个么？
Hoffman... you got a 20 on him?
霍夫曼…找到他了么？
Not yet.
还没
- Hoffman. - Calling.
- 找霍夫曼 - 正在找
How do you explain detective Matthews?
你怎么解释马修警探？
- He's alive. - Six months.
- 他还活着 - 六个月了
- Jigsaw never kept anyone that long. - No one but Amanda Young.
- 竖锯不会让任何人活这么久 - 除了阿曼达·杨
You think he's been fixed?
你说他已经被洗脑了？
Why these six?
为什么这六个人？
Hoffman's a decorated lieutenant. He doesn't fit the profile.
霍夫曼是个中尉 不符合他的挑选方式
That's what you see. But what does he see?
那只是你这么认为而已 但他怎么想？
- Rigg trying to save his two friends. - Maybe.
- 瑞格试着救他的朋友 - 可能
You got names and locations on any of these people?
找到这些人的名字和地址了么？
- Working it. - This is overkill.
- 正在找 - 这是不必要的谋杀
It's a setup to announce Rigg is the accomplice.
宣布瑞格是他的同伙是个阴谋
Or a setup for his alibi. Everyone around him keeps dying.
或者是证明他无辜的 他旁边的人一个一个死掉
Where is he to tell us he's innocent or what the hell these photos
就是为了告诉我们他是清白的 不然这些照片为什么会在这里？
are doing in his apartment? Look there.
看看这个
Move, please.
请让开一下
"Four Walls Build a Home."
“四面墙组成一个家”
What does he want us to see on these walls?
他想让我们从墙上看到什么？
The victims?
受害者？
One of these pictures doesn't belong.
这个照片不是
This is who we're looking for.
这就是我们在找的
Let's talk to her, now.
找她谈谈，现在
Jill Tuck... where is she?
吉尔·塔克…她在哪？
Have them turn off the air in there.
让他们关掉里面的空调
Ms. Tuck,
塔克女士
I' special agent Perez. This is special agent Strahm.
我是特别警探派瑞兹 这是特别警探史特姆
I'd like to apologize for pulling you out of your place of work.
抱歉把你从工作的地方拉过来
What more do you think I can offer you?
你们觉得我们还能给你什么？
My 100 hours of interrogation tapes
100小时的审问
and the volumes of evidence taken from my house
加上我房子里带走的一堆证据
weren't enough for you to understand John?
还不够你们了解约翰？
Actually, it's not John we want to talk about, Ms. Tuck. It's you.
事实上，找你来不是要说约翰的 塔克女士，是你
Me?
我？
Why do you want to talk about me? This isn't about me.
你们为什么要说我？ 这和我无关
So stop wasting both of our time and get to the real reason
那么别浪费彼此的时间 直接说
why you've brought me here.
你们为什么带我来这里吧
Hey, you.
嘿，你！
Let me go!
让我走
Hey!
嘿！
You hear me?
你听到了么？
You fucking hear me,
你TM听到了没？
you fucking motherfucker?
你这个贱人
Who's my girl?
谁是我的女孩？
What the fuck are you looking at?
你TM在看什么？
Huh? What the fuck?
恩？什么狗屁？
Hey, you!
嘿，你！
Sir, sir,
先生，先生
sir, can I help you?
先生，我能帮你什么？
Hello, Officer Rigg. In order for you
你好，瑞格警官 为了让你
to fully understand my way,
完全理解我的行事方式
you must... feel what I feel.
你必须… 感觉我所感觉的
The photo before you is of a man
你前面这张照片
- in desperate need of help. - Sir?
- 是一个需要帮助的绝望的男人 - 先生？
In the next room are the tools to his salvation.
在旁边的房间里有拯救他的工具
His life is in your hands.
他的命在你手里
But in the end only he can save himself.
但是最后只有他才能救他自己
Be careful. There are cameras watching...
小心，那里有摄像头…
and you must hide your identity.
你必须隐藏身份
Make your choice.
自己选择
- Sir? - What the fuck's he doing?
- 先生？ - 他TM在干嘛？
I don't know. You're gonna have to... Look, look,
我不知道，你必须… 看，看
- you're gonna have to go. - People are trying to sleep.
- 你必须走了 - 大家要睡觉了
Yeah, I know people are trying to sleep. You're the one...
是的我知道大家要睡觉了，你就是那个…
Yeah, you can't sleep here. You have to go.
是的，你不能睡在这里 你必须走了
Yeah, well, you can't sleep in here, okay?
是，嗯，你不能睡在这里，知道吗？
That's not a bed. No, you've got to go.
这不是床 不，你必须走
No, you can't use the bathroom. Look, look, no.
不，你不能用洗手间 听着，不
You're gonna have to go. All right...
你必须走了 好吧…
Chance, here, girl.
畅丝，过来，宝贝
Chance. Chance.
畅丝，畅丝
Chance.
畅丝
What are you doing? Come on.
你在干嘛 过来
Chance.
畅丝
Chance, come here. Come here.
畅丝，过来 过来
What you got there, huh? What you got?
你找到了什么？ 你找到了什么？
Come here. Come here. What do you got there?
过来，过来 你找到了什么？
Okay, "Four walls build a home."
好，“四面墙组成一个家”
- Care to shed any light on that? - Light on what?
- 可以解释下吗？ - 解释什么？
On what your photos are doing at the crime scene.
你的照片为什么会出现在犯罪现场？
"Four walls build a home" ring any bells?
“四面墙组成一个家”对你来说意味着什么？
"Cherish your life"?
“珍惜你的生命”
"Cherish your life" is the concept
“珍惜你的生命”这个概念
that this whole clinic was built on...
是整个诊所的经营理念
cherish your life... your life.
珍惜你的生命，你的生命
- That's his motto. - No, it's your motto...
- 那是他的座右铭 - 不，这是你的
of the clinic you run.
这是你诊所的
Fuck, man. I've been here for three fucking hours!
操，我已经来了三小时了
- Shut the fuck up. - You shut up.
- 闭嘴 - 你TM闭嘴
Are you out of your fucking mind?
你TM有病啊？
Hey hey.
嘿，嘿
Hey, guys, come on. Calm down.
嘿，伙计们，好啦，冷静
Cecil!
辛希尔
Stop it, Gus.
停下，革斯
Knock it off now, please!
马上住手，拜托
You don't want to do that.
你不该这么做
- What the fuck is your problem? - You're my problem.
- 你TM有什么毛病？ - 你就是我的毛病
You're becoming everybody else's too.
而且你正在变成其他所有人的
How do you feel about a husband
你觉得这样的一个丈夫怎么样？
who takes a motto from your drug clinic,
他把你诊所用来救人的格言
designed to help people, and twists it
拿出来用来做
into some manic torture mantra?
他折磨别人的座右铭
That part of John has nothing to do with me.
约翰的那一面和我没关系
Look, Ms. Tuck, I just left a room
听着，塔克女士
with more blood on the walls than paint.
我刚从一个墙上血比油漆还多的房间里面出来
Two officers are missing and there's a growing pile of bodies
两个警官失踪了，而且越来越多的人死了
in their wake. And every detail we unearth
所有我们知道的一切
about your Hall of Fame psychopath husband...
和你的神经病丈夫有关的
- Ex. - ...points to you
- 前夫 - 都可以说明
as a possible accomplice.
你可能是同伙
I am just curious as to why.
我只是好奇为什么
You know, there's a lot of people out there
你知道，外面有很多人
looking for answers,
正在寻找
wanting to place blame on someone.
一个替罪羊
That person is you.
那就是你
But you know what the best part is?
而且你知道好在什么地方？
I don't have to convince everybody.
我都不用说服很多人
Just 12 people.
只有12个
Okay, tell me about his workshop.
好，说说他的工作室
Stay there. Let me get the lights.
留在这，我去开灯
Wow, it's big.
哇，好大
This is exactly what you've been looking for.
这就是你一直在找的啊
Nice, huh?
很不错，对不对？
Ta-da!
滴-答
This is the clock? What's so special about it?
就是这个钟？有什么特别的？
Except for the fact the whole deal hung on it?
除了外面很粗糙之外？
The mechanism inside it.
里面的机械
It's 300 years old.
已经有300年了
Still ticking.
还在走
Withstood the test of time.
经受住了时间的考验
Wait till you see this space.
等你来到这里
I've got a surprise for you.
我有个惊喜给你
Why are you doing this?
为什么你要这么做？
Why?
为什么？
This was... this was a mistake.
那是个…那是个错误
It happened a long time ago. And I paid for this.
很久以前的事情了 而且我付出了代价
Just let me... just let me go, okay?
让我… 让我走，好吗？
What's behind that door?
门后面是什么？
"One saves a life. One takes it away."
“有些人救人，有些人杀人”
Try that on the door. Try that.
试试打开门 试试
- Oh, no no. - Get back. Get back. Get back.
- 噢，不，不 - 退后，退后，退后
Let's go. Go.
我们走，走
Eric. Jesus.
艾瑞克，天哪
- Help! Help me! - Get away from there.
- 救我，救我 - 离远点
What do you know about the guy on TV? What do you know about Eric Matthews?
你认识电视里这个人？ 你知道艾瑞克·马修斯？
I don't know who that is.
我不认识他
- What the fuck is this? - I don't know.
- 那TM是什么？ - 我不知道
What are you gonna do to me?
你要对我做什么？
If you are playing this tape, then you are one step closer
如果你在播放这个带子 那么你离
to truly understanding how to save a life.
完全了解如何拯救一个人又近一步了
As an officer of the law, you find yourself torn...
作为一个警察 你发现你被撕得…
- Who is that? - Shut up.
- 那是谁？ - 闭嘴
Is the man before you a victim or a perpetrator of violence?
你前面这个人是个受害者 还是暴力杀人犯？
You sick fuck.
你这恶心的贱人
His salvation is out of your hands.
他的拯救已经不在你手里了
It is your choice, if you wish,
如果你想的话，你可以
to put it into his own.
让他自己来
Once this lesson is learned,
如果你学会了这堂课
you will find yourself one step closer
你会发现你离
to truly saving Eric Matthews.
如何真正拯救艾瑞克·马修斯更近了
Without you this man's game cannot begin.
没有你的话这个人不会开始游戏
Force him into position to face his demons
强迫他就位，面对他的魔鬼
and let him make the decision.
并且让他自己做决定
Shh. Don't wake up our neighbors.
嘘，别吵醒邻居
Fuck. Is this what you do with your spare time, huh?
操，这就是你平时打发时间做的？
No.
不
Take it all, little girl. Be a good little whore.
快点宝贝，做个小婊子
Get on the fucking bed. Get on the bed!
滚到床上去，滚到床上去
Move!
快！
Strap yourself in. Strap yourself in.
把自己套进去 套进去
Please don't make me do this. I know...
求你了别这样 我知道…
I know I was wrong. I know.
我知道我错了 我知道
Hurry up. Hurry up.
快点，快点
Put your fucking hands up.
举起你TMD手来
I don't know. I don't know.
我不知道，我不知道
I' sorry. I' sorry.
对不起，对不起
Listen, I' really sorry.
听着，对不起
What does that say? What does that say?
（给他拯救自己性命的工具） 那说什么？那说什么？
What is that?
那是什么？
- Take them. - Why?
- 拿着 - 为什么？
Hello, lvan. As a voyeur,
你好，艾尔文 作为一个窥探癖
you've kept photos of those you have victimized.
你保留的这些照片，你受害者的照片
- Let me go! - Can you see the pain
- 让我走 - 你能看到你给这些人
you have brought them?
带来的痛苦吗？
You have torn apart their lives.
你把他们的生活撕碎
You have used your body as an instrument of abuse.
你用你的身体当作虐待工具
Now I give you the chance to decide
现在我给你机会让你决定
what is more important...
什么是更重要的
your eyes which have led you blindly astray
让你误入歧途的眼睛
or your body which has caused those around you endless suffering.
还是你让身边的人受苦的身体
You have been handed the tools which can save your life.
你手上的就是拯救你生命的工具
Decide quickly, though. In 60 seconds
快点决定，否则 六十秒之后
the choice will be made for you.
我会帮你决定的
（感受我的感受）
I can do it. One more. I can do it.
我能做到的，再来一个 我能做到
(作一个拯救生命的老师，回到一切的初始)
You're gonna have to tell me how you got those bruises on your hand and your neck.
告诉我你手上脖子上的淤青怎么来的？
Was this an accident or did someone do this to you on purpose?
是不小心还是有人故意的？
You can stop it from happening if you tell me the truth.
如果告诉我，下次就不会发生了
Take a seat, please.
请坐
I want to go home now.
我想回家
The son of a bitch is lying.
那个狗娘养的在撒谎
He's done this before. She's allowing it.
他以前就做过了 他老婆居然不管
The child's story doesn't corroborate. What can I do?
那个小孩的故事也不合理 我能做什么
Jane, I can't let you go home right now, okay?
珍，你现在还不能回家，好吗？
Go back to class, honey.
回教室去，孩子
I told you, Officers, sometimes these kids...
我跟你说过了，警官
they just get out of control.
孩子总是会捣蛋
- Get your hands off me! - Hey, take it easy.
- 把手拿开！ - 嘿，别紧张
Rigg! Rigg!
瑞格！瑞格！
No. Get out. Get out now.
不，出去，快点出去
You just made the biggest mistake of your life.
你犯了你这辈子最大的错误
You hear me? I will take him
听到了吗？我要告他
for everything he's got, that fucking cocksucker.
告到他一无所有，那个王八蛋
That's sweet, Ms. Tuck,
听起来不错，塔克太太
but if you love the guy so much, why leave him?
但如果你那么爱他，为什么要离开他？
- He left me long before I left him. - Okay, people break up.
- 是早就他离开了我 - 好吧，分手很正常
Relationships end. It's called life.
关系早晚会结束，这就是生活
I mean, he started massacring people.
他开始虐杀别人
- Gideon meant everything to him. - Gideon? I' sorry, who?
- 他想的全是黑暗执政官 - 执政官，抱歉，谁？
Do you know anything about the Chinese zodiac?
你知道中国有个“黄道带”吗？
Aw, Jill, no no.
啊，吉尔，不，不
I didn't just get pregnant.
我不仅是怀孕那么简单
It was carefully planned.
约翰把一切都
Everything with John was.
计划得很好
- Thanks. - See you.
- 谢谢 - 再见
- Bye-bye. - Bye. Let me get that for you.
- 再见 - 再见，我帮你开门
Thank you.
谢谢
- Thanks. Have a good night. - You too.
- 谢谢，祝你愉快 - 你也是
- Good night. - Good night.
- 晚安 - 晚安
Hey, honey, you want some company?
宝贝，想要个人陪吗？
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
You know what this building is?
你知道这是什么地方吗？
It's a health clinic.
这是保健所
You're a beautiful girl. Go home.
你是个漂亮女孩，回家吧
My jacket. I forgot my jacket.
我的外衣，我忘了拿我的外衣
- I forgot my jacket. - Cecil, no.
- 我忘了外衣 - 辛希尔，别
Oh, please please, Jill. It's right there.
求你了，吉尔，就在那边
Look, it's right there. Please please. Come on.
看，就在那边，求你了
Thank you.
谢谢
Thanks.
Listen to me. I don't want to hurt you, all right?
听着，我不想伤害你，好吗？
You're gonna open up that fucking door.
把那该死的门打开
Open that fucking door. Open it.
把那该死的门打开，打开
Open it.
打开
Fuck! What fucking key?
操！哪一把钥匙？
- What key? - That one.
- 哪一把？ - 这把
Fuck.
干！
Fucking stay there.
别TMD动
Cecil?
辛希尔？
Don't cry. No no, hey, you're gonna be okay.
别哭，别，你不会有事的
Fuck.
操！
I need some help here.
我需要帮助
Orderly.
奥得利
This is my wife. She's pregnant.
她是我妻子，她怀孕了
- How far along is she, sir? - Seven months.
- 孩子多大了，先生？ - 7个月
All I wanted to do was help them.
我只是想帮他们
You can't help them.
你不能帮他们
They have to help themselves.
他们必须自救
Okay, let's review:
好，我们来总结下
Girl loves boy. Boy loves girl.
女孩爱男孩，男孩爱女孩
Boy gets girl pregnant. Girl loses baby.
男孩让女孩怀孕，女孩流产了
Boy turns into a serial killer.
男孩就变成了连环杀手
Jill, I' not buying it.
吉尔，我才不信呢
You're gonna want to take a look at this.
你得来看看这些
All right, she doesn't leave.
好，她不准离开
He's been identified as lvan Landsness.
他的身份证实为艾尔文·兰兹里斯
Acquitted of rape three times.
三次强奸指控失败
Had to gouge out his own eyes in order to release himself.
他必须凿出自己的眼睛来赎罪
How does something like this get into a motel room undetected?
这种事在旅馆发生，怎么没人发现？
Piece by piece.
一步一步的
The room's been rented for the past six days
过去6天，这房间被一个律师租下来了
to a lawyer named Art Blank. Get this: He went missing two weeks ago.
他叫亚特·布兰克，还有 这位律师两周前失踪了
Run his name. Get his addresses.
查查这个名字，找到他的地址
Two out of five people on Officer Rigg's apartment walls are dead.
瑞格家里，五个人有三个都死了
Every partner he's ever worked with... dead.
和他合作过的每一个搭档，都死了
Rigg didn't kill lvan. Ivan made his own choice.
瑞格并没有杀艾尔文，艾尔文自己做的选择
Isn't that the whole Jigsaw mantra?
这是竖锯颂歌吗？
This wasn't about lvan. It wasn't his test.
跟艾尔文没关系，这是他的考验
It was about Rigg.
是瑞格的考验
Look at these photos. Tell me how you feel.
看看这些照片，告诉我你的想法
Look at these women and tell me how you feel.
看看这些女人，告诉我你有什么想法
- Angry. Enraged. - Exactly.
- 愤怒，暴怒 - 没错
The pimp, the rapist... Jigsaw wanted Rigg to see what he sees.
皮条客，强奸犯，竖锯要让瑞格看到他所看到的
He wants him to feel what he feels.
感觉到他的感受
This wasn't about Rigg saving his friends.
这不是瑞格如何救朋友的故事
He's being recruited.
他被征募了
Thanks. Art Blank's got a bunch of properties.
谢谢，亚特·布兰克有好几个住处
Last known address is a couple of blocks from here.
最近的住址，离这里只有几个街区
- Right side clear. - Left side clear.
- 右边安全 - 左边安全
- Clear. - Clear.
- 安全 - 安全
Clear.
安全
（打开门你就能找到我） （靠得太近，你就会有危险…靠后）
What does this mean?
这意味着什么？
We're the two Jigsaw targets.
我们现在是竖锯的猎物了
Fuck you.
操你
Hey.
嘿
Hey. Hey.
嘿，嘿
Hey, asshole, you jump off that block,
嘿，王八蛋，你从冰块上下来
you electrocute him.
你就电死他
If that ice had melted more, he'd be fried. You understand?
如果冰块继续融化，他就被烤熟，听懂了吗？
Listen to him.
听他的
You just made the biggest mistake of your life,
你犯了这辈子最大的错误
- cocksucker! - Calm down.
- 王八蛋！ - 冷静
We'll get somebody to take a look at it, all right?
我们找个人来帮你看看，好吗？
My client has a broken nose and a fractured cheekbone.
我的客户鼻子和颊骨都被打碎了
Administrative leave with pay is not acceptable.
仅是些行政赔偿是不够的
The IA investigation is underway.
内部调查员马上过来
Into this precinct? Wow. What's that gonna get me, huh?
到这个地界上来？能给我带来什么？
- The truth. - I'll tell you what the truth is.
- 真相 - 我来告诉你什么是真相
The truth is, I have an eyewitness.
真相是，我有目击证人
The man's wife? She stands to gain as much as he does
他的老婆？她等着分他老公的钱呢
if there were to be a financial settlement,
如果有经济赔偿的话
which is not gonna happen because he's lying.
但不会有，因为那家伙撒谎了
He attacked Officer Rigg first.
他先攻击了瑞格警官
That's according to whom?
这是谁说的？
Me. I saw the whole thing.
我，我见证了整件事
You want to testify before the grand jury?
你能在陪审团面前指正吗？
I've already signed IA's affidavit. The charges are being dismissed.
我已经在内部调查报告上宣誓了 赔偿已经被取消
Oh, you guys are... you're good.
你们这群家伙…你们够狠
You know, you're obviously as thick as thieves in this precinct.
在这件案子上，你们就跟窃贼一样可耻
But it'll come back to you. You know that, right?
你们会遭到报应的，你们知道，对吧？
I mean, one day someday it will. It will come back to you.
有一天，一定会有一天 报应会降临
You understand?
你懂吗？
Motherfucker.
婊子养的
Hey, do you understand?
嘿，你懂了吗？
Okay.
懂了
Motherfucker.
婊子养的
You're gonna have to tell me how you got
你必须要告诉我
those bruises on your hand and your neck.
你的手和脖子上怎么会有瘀伤
Rigg! Rigg!
瑞格！瑞格！
I did it! I won!
我做到了，我赢了
What the hell did you do?
你TMD干了什么？
L...
我…
What's happening?
发生了什么？
The human body is a fascinating organism.
人体是很奇妙的有机系统
It can withstand the most brutal injury...
可以承受最凶狠的伤害
and yet repair itself miraculously.
然后奇迹般的自我修复
But you know this all too well.
但你很清楚
How many broken bones have you suffered
你有多少骨头被你丈夫
at the hands of your husband?
亲手打断？
How many flesh wounds have you endured?
你有多少血淋淋的伤口？
Help!
救命！
With time, the bruises have healed, but your pain has not.
随着时间消逝，伤口愈合了，但你的痛苦没有
Today I empower you to take control of your life.
今天我给你把握自己命运的力量
Can you disconnect from the one thing
你能从让自己和其他人
that has brought you and others so much pain?
从极大的痛苦中解脱出来吗？
With time your wounds will heal.
随着时间消逝，你的伤痕会愈合
His, however, will not.
但是，他的不会
Remove the ties that bind...
把束缚解开…
Get me out of here!
放我走！
...or bleed to death from you inactivity.
或者因为软弱流血而亡
The choice is yours.
你自己选择
Okay. Okay okay!
好，好，好！
Here we go.
我拔
I' sorry.
对不起
Morgan, Morgan, what the fuck are you doing?
莫根，莫根，你TMD的在干什么？
Help me. Please help me. I can't do this.
救救我，求你救救我，我做不到
- Please help me! - Calm down.
- 求你救救我 - 冷静点
No, don't go. Don't go. Don't go. Wait for me.
不，不要走，不要走，救救我
Please get me out. Please get me out.
求你救救我，求你救救我
Don't. Don't go. Don't leave me here.
不要走，别把我扔在这儿
Help me down.
救救我
Hello, Officer Rigg. What have you learned thus far?
你好，瑞格警官，现在你学到了什么？
Experience is a harsh teacher.
经验是严厉的老师
First comes the test.
先考验你
Second comes the lesson.
然后给你上一课
If you are to save as I save
如果你像我一样治病救人
then you will see that the person before you
你就会明白你面前的人
is but a student.
不过是你的学生
So I ask you, Officer Rigg,
瑞格警官，我问你个问题
has the pupil learned her lesson?
你的学生学会了吗？
Has she been taught the error of her ways?
她知道自己犯的过错了吗？
Does she now
她现在
- view the world differently? - Please help.
- 明白世上的艰难了吗？ - 救救我
Officer Rigg, the key to this person's freedom
瑞格警官，这个人的自由
lies in the palm of your hand.
就掌握在你的手中
But only after she has done her own part
但只有她做完自己的那部分
can you play your role in her salvation.
你才能扮演拯救的角色
Once judgment has been made, though,
而且只有审判结束以后
the key to finding your next destination
你下一站的指示
is just off the map.
就在图后
- Who did this to you? - I don't know.
- 这是谁干的？ - 我不知道
Help, please. Help, please.
救救我 救救我
Stay still. I' gonna try to take this out.
别动，我来想办法把它拔出来
Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢你，谢谢你
Oh, fuck.
干！
That's it. "Just off the map."
就是这样，“就在图后”
Just off the map.
就在图后
Tracy.
翠西
"Go home."
“回家”
Where is she?
她在哪儿？
I' so cold. Please.
冷死了，求你了
I want to live.
我不想死
You have to save yourself.
你必须拯救自己
Don't leave me. Please don't leave.
不要离开我，求你不要离开
Help me, please. Don't leave.
救救我，不要走
I want to stop playing.
我不想再玩下去了
Why don't you fucking kill me?
你TMD为什么不杀了我？
No.
不
- Shut up! - I don't want to play anymore.
- 闭嘴！ - 我不想再玩了
"Save as I save."
“跟我一样救人”
So what did he do, free her and let him die?
他干了什么，放走她，让他死？
This guy didn't have a chance. He's got rods going through
这个家伙本来就没希望了 这些棍子全都
every major artery in his body. "Your life is in her hands."
穿过他的要害 “你的命在她手里”
Rigg didn't kill this guy. His wife did.
不是瑞格杀了这家伙，是他老婆
She identified Officer Rigg, said he saved her.
她认出了瑞格警官，说是他拯救了她
- Saved? - Yeah.
- 拯救？ - 是的
She passed Rigg's judgment, got fixed and got her freedom back.
她通过了瑞格的审判，重获了自由
- Yeah. - Second address?
- 是的 - 第二个地址？
Really? Okay, yeah. That's good. Good.
真的？好的，不错，不错
But I still need that address. Text me.
但我仍需要地址，发给我
I just found out something interesting about the three people in the traps.
我从调查中刚刚发现，这三个接受考验的家伙
They were all represented by a lawyer named Art Blank.
都请了同一个律师，叫亚特·布兰克
- He got them all off? - Yeah. But wait, it gets better.
- 他替所有人全部代理？ - 是的，等下，还有更好的
He's also Jill Tuck's lawyer.
他也是吉尔·塔克的律师
Look out!
小心！
- The lair... where's the lair? - Raided. It doesn't exist.
- 他的巢穴，巢穴在哪儿？ - 找过了，根本就没有
Jigsaw wanted us to find that place. Where's the new game being played?
竖锯想让我们找到他的巢穴 新的游戏在哪里上演？
We find that place... we find Rigg.
我们找到那个地方，就能找到瑞格
We got a second address. There's a co-owner.
我们找到了第二个地址，另个人也拥有它
- Who? - Jill Tuck.
- 谁？ - 吉尔·塔克
- Jill Tuck? Where's the building? - Here. This building.
- 吉尔·塔克？房子在哪儿？ - 这里，就在这栋楼
Hello, Agent Perez.
你好，派瑞兹干员
And welcome to the world that you have long studied.
欢迎来到你一直在调查着的世界
Your partner Agent Strahm
你的搭档史特姆干员
will soon take the life of an innocent man.
马上就要夺走一个无辜的人的性命
Heed my warning, Agent Perez.
仔细听我的警告，派瑞兹干员
Your next move is critical.
你的下一步很关键
Open the door...
打开门…
What is that?
这是什么？
I got you.
被耍了
Paramedics!
救护！
Help!
帮忙！
Stay with me. Okay, come on.
别放弃，听我说
Shallow breaths. Come on.
慢慢呼吸，呼吸
Stay with me. All right.
别放弃，没事
All right. You're gonna be fine. You're gonna be fine.
你不会有事，不会有事
Hey.
嘿
Hey, you. Come here.
你，过来
Look.
看看
Hey. Hey.
嘿，嘿
Come on.
过来
Hey. Hey.
嘿，嘿
Fuck.
操！
- Stop. Stop. - Son of a bitch!
- 停下 - 婊子养的
Fuck.
操！
Stop. Fuck.
停下，干
Hey.
嘿
Listen to me. I' not the one you've got to worry about.
听着，我不是你要防的人
You understand me? I' not the one you've got to worry about,
你听懂了吗，我不是你要防的人
asshole.
王八蛋
As a matter of fact, I recommend you stay alive
实际上，我建议你活下去
until the fucking clock counts down.
等到时钟走到点
Here's the good news: If this other guy passes his test,
告诉你个好消息，如果另个家伙通过了测试
the three of us can go free.
我们三个就解放了
Hey, look at me.
看着我
Look at me.
If you don't stay on the block, your partner gets electrocuted.
如果你撑不到时候，你的搭档就会被电死
Now for my final task.
而我的任务
There you go.
给你
Live or die.
活或死
You make the choice.
自己选择
Mrs. Perez?
派瑞兹太太？
Hi. This is Peter Strahm. I work with your daughter Lindsay.
你好，我是彼特·史特姆 我和你的女儿琳达丝是同事
Yeah. I have some bad news.
我有个坏消息
See that, Jill? That's a federal fucking indictment. It's got your name on it.
看到没？这是联邦指控 你的名字也在上面
Wanna put somebody else's name on it? You start talking to me, okay?
想把其他人名字也放上面？ 你跟我谈谈，好吗？
What's with the doll? What's with the tricycle?
这玩具怎么回事？三轮车怎么回事？
Who were John's business associates before he went insane?
在约翰发疯之前，谁是他的生意伙伴？
He wasn't the associate type.
他不需要伙伴
Where the hell is Art Blank?
亚特·布兰克在TM哪儿？
Obstruction of justice. Aiding and abetting.
妨碍司法，协同，教唆
Conspirator to murder.
杀人同谋
Talk to me!
跟我说！
In 15 minutes, more people are gonna die, Jill... police officers.
15分钟以后，更多人会死…警官
He's a business partner. He's a friend.
他的生意伙伴，他的朋友
He's the accomplice we have been looking for
他是我们要找的帮凶
and he is your fucking lawyer.
他是你TMD律师
You see this? This is my partner's blood.
你看到了吗？这是我搭档的血
She's fighting for her life right now
她正在死亡线上挣扎
because of your lunatic husband.
因为你的疯子丈夫
What happened between Jigsaw and Art Blank?
竖锯和亚特·布兰克之间发生了什么？
John?
约翰?
John.
约翰
I guess he's not here either.
我想他也不在这儿
What the fuck is this place, Jill?
这是TMD什么地方？
- Don't be mad. - What?
- 不要抓狂 - 什么？
Hey, are you all right?
你还好吗？
You weren't returning my calls, buddy.
你没有回我电话，伙计
Listen, John, I...
听着，约翰，我…
I' sorry. I understand.
抱歉，我明白
What happened was a tragedy.
那是个惨剧
But I gotta tell you...
但我要跟你说…
listen, John, I gotta tell you, those buildings we're working on...
听着，约翰，我要告诉你 你工作的这个房子
You take 'em. You give my share to Jill.
你留着吧，给吉尔她那部分
That's not the way it works, John. You see, we're partners.
事情不是这样的，约翰，你看，我们是搭档
Your designs will make those buildings special.
你的设计会把这里变的特别
We've got 40 families ready to move in... 40 families, John,
有40户人家会搬进来…40个家庭
low-income families.
低收入家庭
You can't just walk away.
你不能就这样撒手不管
You're their savior, John.
你是他们的救世主
Get the fuck out of here.
滚出去
Who are you talking to like that? It's me, John.
你为什么用这种口气跟我说话？是我啊
- Did you hear what I said? - Oh, I heard you, John.
- 你没听到我说的吗？ - 我听到了，约翰
Get the fuck...
滚出去
You heard me.
你听到了
Okay, John. You take good care of yourself.
好吧，好好照顾自己
Gimme a call when you're feeling better.
你感觉好点以后，给我打个电话
He blamed me.
他怪我
I don't think he could ever forgive me.
我想他永远都不会原谅我
In his mind our time was over.
在他心里，我们完了
He was diagnosed with cancer soon after that.
不久后他被诊断出癌症
Did you try to contact him again?
你有再和他联系吗？
I tried.
我试过
But a different person crawled out of the wreckage.
但另一个他从车祸中爬出来
Someone else survived.
另一个他活了下来
- I asked you not to come here. - I need to talk to you.
- 我跟你说过不要到这儿来 - 我要跟你谈谈
John, John,
约翰，约翰
look at this. What is this, hmm?
看这个，这是什么？
Why do you have Cecil's picture?
你为什么会有辛希尔的照片？
What have you done to him?
你对他干了什么？
I told him not to take life for granted.
我告诉他不要浪费生命
I want to play a game.
我想跟你做个游戏
Your life is a lie.
你的一生都是谎言
Now comes your moment of truth.
是时候面对真相了
As a drug user and a hustler,
作为一个隐君子和皮条客
you've played roulette with other people's lives.
你把他人的性命当成赌注
Today you play with your own.
今天你赌自己的性命
Fuck.
干！
Fuck!
Hey, it's you.
是你
You did this to me.
这是你干的
No, you did this to yourself.
这是你自己干的
Your greed took the life of an innocent child.
你的贪婪夺走了一个无辜孩子的生命
Could you give me time to explain, please?
给我点时间解释下，求你了
I can't give you time. No one can.
我无法给你时间，没人可以
Time's an illusion.
时间是幻象
Look, look, I' sorry. I' sorry.
听着，我很抱歉，抱歉
I forgive you, Cecil. I do.
我原谅你了，辛希尔，真的
Addiction has ruined your life.
毒品毁了你的生活
I' bleeding, man.
我在流血
Please just let me go.
求你放我走吧
I could let you go.
我可以让你走
That wouldn't serve you.
但那样帮不了你
I'll tell you what I will do, though. I'll give you a tool
我告诉你我可以为你做什么，我给你工具
to reclaim your life,
引向你的新生
to discard the vices that have so corrupted your soul.
抛弃那些腐化了你灵魂的恶习
I don't have a fucking soul.
我没有什么该死的灵魂
Maybe you will in the next life, Cecil.
也许你来生会有
You see, things aren't sequential.
世界上没有因果循环
Good doesn't lead to good, nor bad to bad.
好人未必好报，恶人未必恶报
People steal, don't get caught,
小偷，不一定被逮到
live the good life.
还活得很滋润
Others lie, cheat
撒谎，欺骗的人
and get elected.
被选为领袖
Some people stop to help a stranded motorist
而停下来帮助遇难者的人
and get taken out by a speeding semi.
却因超速驾驶而被逮捕
There's no accounting for it.
数不胜数
How you play the cards you're dealt... that's all that matters.
如何打出你手上的牌，才是最重要的
Look at me.
看着我
Do you understand what I' saying to you?
你明白我跟你说的话吗？
Oh, yeah.
是的
I understand.
我明白
You're fucking nuts!
你TMD的疯子！
Whoa! What the fuck is that?
这是什么鬼东西？
It's the tool...
这就是你的工具
the tool that's going to save your life.
用来拯救你的灵魂
I want to play a game.
我要跟你玩个游戏
Your life is a lie, Cecil.
你的一生都是谎言
Now comes your moment of truth.
是时候面对真相了
As a drug addict and a thief,
作为一个隐君子和皮条客
you've preyed on the kindness of others
你靠他人的仁慈生存
to fuel your addiction.
支付你的毒品
Today we're bringing
今天我们来
the ugliness inside you out into the open.
把你体内的丑恶都释放出来
Now in order for you to stay alive
想要活下去
we have to match your face
你必须要用自己的脸
with the ugliness of your soul.
来面对你灵魂的丑恶
Just lean forward into the knives with your face.
把你的脸靠向这些利刃
Press hard enough
使够力气
and you'll release the arm and the leg restraints
你就能把你的手和腿从束缚中
that bind you.
解脱出来
Press hard, though.
只有使够力量
And you'll be free.
就能自由
You sick fuck! Fuck you!
你个变态狂，操你妈！
Or you can sit idly and bleed out on the floor.
或者你可以什么多不做 看着自己的血流光
Live or die, Cecil.
生或者死
Make your choice.
自己选择
Fuck you, you sick fuck!
操你妈，变态狂！
Help!
救命！
You're dead.
你死定了
You're fucking dead.
你TMD死定了
Fucking dead.
死定了
What's happened to you?
你到底怎么了？
What's happened to me?
我到底怎么了？
Now you don't come back.
你不许再回来
You do it for yourself if you can't do it for me.
如果你不能为我做，就替自己想想
I lost him too.
我也失去了孩子
"Four Walls Build a Home."
“四面墙组成一个家”
Your son was named after John's first building, right?
你的孩子是以约翰的第一栋房子起名的，对吧？
- Yes. - Where is it?
- 是的 - 房子在哪儿？
Where is it? Where is it?
房子在哪儿？
Where is it?
（耐心，记住你在救“谁”，有的是时间）
What the fuck does that mean?
这TM是什么意思？
（最终测试）
Fuck. Oh, fuck.
操，操
You'd better hope he doesn't come through that door.
你最好祷告他不要从那扇门里冲出来
Who? Who's coming through the door?
谁？谁会从门里冲出来？
Who is it?
是谁？
Where the fuck are you?
你TMD在哪儿？
Gideon Meat Packing, 11235 Blake drive.
吉登肉店停车场，布莱克大道11235号
I don't have two minutes.
我等不了两分钟
（看我所看到的）
（感受我的感受）
（以我的审判来审判）
（你学会“谁”是你真正要解救的了吗）
Who's coming through the door?
谁会从门里冲出来？
Fuck.
干
Congratulations, Art.
恭喜你，亚特
Who is it?
是谁？
Who's coming through the door?
谁会从门里冲出来？
Here he comes.
他来了
Who the fuck is it?
是TMD谁？
Shit.
操
Fix me, motherfucker!
杀了我吧，狗娘养的！
I' standing right here.
我就站在这儿
Your time's running out.
你没时间了
Please think about what you're doing.
请考虑下你在做什么
Think about what you promised me.
想想你跟我承诺了什么
Think about tomorrow.
想想明天
Lynn?
林？
Lynn! Lynn!
林！林！
Who is it?
是谁？
What is that?
那是什么？
This will release us when the timer's up.
时间到了，这东西会放了我们
Release me!
放了我！
Which is it gonna be, Jeff?
你如何选择，杰夫？
Live or die, Jeff.
生或者死
You've got a choice.
自己选择
I forgive you.
我原谅你
Jeff.
杰夫
Jeff!
杰夫！
- Eric! - Don't open the door!
- 艾瑞克！ - 不要开那扇门！
What the fuck?
搞什么鬼？
Shit.
操
"Open the door and you will find me."
“打开门你就能找到我”
- Let me see your fucking hands. - Where is my daughter, you mother?
- 把TMD的手举起来 - 我的女儿在哪儿，婊子？
Fuck.
操
Jesus.
天呐
- Fuck! - Aw, you stupid motherfucker.
- 操！ - 哦，你个婊子养的蠢蛋
- What did you do? - I had more time.
- 你干了什么？ - 我还有时间
- I still had fucking time. - Why did you open that door?
- 我还有时间 - 你为什么要开那扇门？
- You fucking did this! - No, you idiot.
- 是你TMD干的！ - 不，你个蠢猪
No, Jigsaw's testing you, you fucking piece of shit.
竖锯在考验你，你这个蠢货
Put your fucking hands where I can see them!
让我看到你的手！
- Jigsaw's fucking testing you. - Don't fucking move!
- 竖锯在TMD考验你 - 别TMD动！
Hello, Officer Rigg.
你好，瑞格警官
If you are hearing this, then you have reached
如果你听到了这个 代表你已经成功的
detective Matthews and detective Hoffman
在90分钟内找到了
in under 90 minutes,
马修斯和霍夫曼警探
resulting in their deaths.
并导致了他们的死亡
The rules were clear.
规则很简单
You were warned.
我警告过你
- It's Kerry! - Do not go through that door.
- 是凯瑞！ - 不要穿过那扇门
You know never to go through an unsecured door, ever.
你知道千万不要穿过不安全的门
Tonight you face your obsession.
今晚你面对你的梦魇
What you can't do is save everyone.
你不能拯救每个人
Will you learn how to let go?
你学到如何放手了吗？
- Eric is still out there, man. - It's time to let go.
- 艾瑞克还在受折磨，兄弟 - 是时候放手了
Detective Matthews has but 90 minutes.
马修斯警探只有90分钟
I recommend you stay alive
我建议你活下去
until the fucking clock counts down.
知道时钟到点
They had to save themselves.
他们必须拯救自己
Take 'em.
拿着
Their salvation was out of your hands.
他们的救赎，你无能为力
Time was on your side,
你有的是时间
but your obsession wouldn't let you wait.
但是你的困绕让你等不下去
Instead of saving detective Matthews,
你杀了马修斯警探
you cost him his life.
而不是救他
You failed your final test.
你的最终测试失败了
What I don't understand is how the hell could Jigsaw do all this?
我不明白的是竖锯怎么做到这些的？
He was damn near on his deathbed the last time we saw him.
我上次见他的时候，他都快死了
I' not so sure he did.
我不觉得他快死了
- This wasn't done by Amanda Young. - Excuse me?
- 这不是阿曼达·杨干的 - 说什么？
- She couldn't get her up there alone. - John Kramer was...
- 她一个人不可能把她吊那么高 - 约翰·克里莫他…
He's brains, not brawn.
他只能动脑子，不能做体力
We're here to find the person helping Jigsaw and Amanda Young.
我们必须要找到帮助 竖锯和阿曼达·杨的那个人
Looks like another doctor went missing from the hospital.
看来医院里面又有一个医生失踪了
You go home.
你回家吧
We chose this.
我们选择的
Game over.
游戏结束
You feel you now have control, don't you?
你以为你掌握了局势，对吧？
You think you will walk away untested?
你以为你可以不通过测试就离开？
I promise that my work will continue.
我保证我的事业会继续
That I have ensured.
我保证
By hearing this tape some will assume
听到这个磁带，有人会以为
that this is over.
一切结束了
But I am still among you.
但我仍然活在你们中间
You think it's over just because I am dead?
你以为我死了，就全结束了？
It's not over. The games have just begun.
没有结束，游戏才刚刚开始